http://youtu.be/QaxFxLZk9mo
http://youtu.be/QaxFxLZk9mo
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: In this short video,
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: trong video ngắn này,
we are going to answer the question, what
tôi sẽ trả lời câu hỏi,
is a logic high and a logic low on our microcontroller?
cái gì là mức logic cao và mức logic thấp trên con vi điều khiển của chúng ta?
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: OK, so we go to the table of contents.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: đúng rồi, hãy hình vào mục lục.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: And we see in our chapter 24,
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: chương 24.
it will tell us what ratings are.
nó sẽ nói cho ta biết.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: OK.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: đúng vậy.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: And it will tell us our levels.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: nói về mức logic của chúng ta.
So let's look that up.
Nhìn vào đây.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: OK.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: OK.
Section 24.3.
Phần 24.3.
So here, in section 24.3, it's going to tell us what the voltages are.
Ở phần 24.3 này nói cho ta về mức điện áp.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: So we want to look up
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: ta cần kiếm
what a voltage high and a voltage low ranges are.
giá trị điện áp cao và điện áp thấp.
So we'll see that for a high, the lowest high voltage you can have is 2.4V.
Cho mức điện áp cao, giá trị tối thiểu là 2.4V.
And for a low, the maximum you can have is 0.4V.
cho mức thấp, giá trị tối đa là 0.4V.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: Yes.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: chính xác.
And similarly, we can see what voltages it
Tương tự, ta có thể thấy mức điện áp
thinks are high and low for the inputs.
cao và thấp cho input.
So these are the VIH and VIL.
Đây là VIH và VIL.
And we can use these equations here to calculate
Ta có thể xài những công thức này để tính toán
what the voltages will be that the microcontroller will
mức điện áp mà vi điều khiển sẽ
consider an input high or an input low.
coi là input mức cao và input mức thấp.
There we have it.
Vậy là ta có nó.